<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EMI Group on EMI Research Group</title><link>http://localhost:1313/</link><description>Recent content in EMI Group on EMI Research Group</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Operando X-ray Techniques</title><link>http://localhost:1313/research/operando-xray-techniques/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/research/operando-xray-techniques/</guid><description>Observing reactions under operating conditions to understand how catalysts and functional materials transform during operation.</description></item><item><title>Robert Weatherup</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/robert-weatherup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/robert-weatherup/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Rob is Professor of Energy Materials (2024) in the Department of Materials, and a Tutorial Fellow of the Queen’s College, University of Oxford. He received a PhD from University of Cambridge (2013) for work on “In Situ Studies of Catalytic Graphene Growth” with Prof. Stephan Hofmann. He went on to a stipendiary research fellowship by St. John’s College, Cambridge (2013-2017) during which he spent two years in the USA as a Marie Skłodowska Curie Fellow (2015-2017) at Lawrence Berkley National Laboratory hosted by Prof. Miquel Salmeron. This involved the development of new methods to extend X-ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy to the atmospheric pressure regime, in order to study solid-liquid and solid-gas interfaces. After a brief return to Cambridge, working in the group of Prof. Clare Grey on anodes for Li-ion batteries, he became a Diamond-Manchester research fellow (2018-2019) based at Diamond Light Source on the Harwell campus. He joined Oxford as an Associate Professor in October 2019, and continues to work extensively at facilities on the Harwell campus. He is the Research Area Lead for Electrochemical Systems within the Henry Royce Institute (2021), a visiting scientist at Diamond Light Source (2019), and a CAMS-UK Fellow (2019).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Electrocatalysis</title><link>http://localhost:1313/research/electrocatalysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/research/electrocatalysis/</guid><description>Investigating electrocatalytic processes for water splitting, CO₂ conversion, and sustainable ammonia synthesis.</description></item><item><title>Rechargeable Battery Interfaces</title><link>http://localhost:1313/research/rechargeable-batteries/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/research/rechargeable-batteries/</guid><description>Understanding degradation mechanisms in lithium-ion batteries through operando studies and advanced spectroscopy.</description></item><item><title>Erik Björklund</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/erik-bjorklund/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/erik-bjorklund/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Erik Björklund started as a postdoctoral research assistant at Oxford in November 2019, working in the Faraday degradation project in Robert Weatherup’s Group. He received his PhD from Uppsala University for analysing how commercial electrode materials degrade during usage. He is mainly focused on combining the understanding of the electrochemistry with the surface degradation product on the outermost nanometres of the electrodes by using XPS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With his spare time Erik likes to read books, visit parks and play the board game, Go.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Peixi Cong</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/peixi-cong/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/peixi-cong/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Peixi is a postdoctoral research associate at the Materials Department at the University of Oxford in Prof R Weatherup’s research group. He received a PhD from University College London for the work on &amp;ldquo;The application of X-ray techniques to identify deactivation processes and active species in novel catalytic materials&amp;rdquo; under Prof. A Beale&amp;rsquo;s supervision. This work focused on the in situ and operando characterisation of deactivation and active species in catalytic materials with combined X-ray spectroscopic and scattering techniques.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Electrolyte Solvation and Transport</title><link>http://localhost:1313/research/electrolyte-solvation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/research/electrolyte-solvation/</guid><description>Understanding how electrolyte solvation structure affects transport properties and electrochemical stability.</description></item><item><title>Longxiang Liu</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/longxiang-liu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/longxiang-liu/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Longxiang completed his PhD at UCL Department of Chemistry in 2023. His PhD project focused on the design and characterization of carbon-based materials for electrochemical hydrogen peroxide production. He joined Robert Weatherup&amp;rsquo;s group as a postdoctoral researcher in October 2023.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Conor Phelan</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/conor-phelan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/conor-phelan/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Conor joined he group in October 2020 to investigate the electrode-electrolyte interfaces in rechargeable Alkali-Ion batteries. He obtained a degree in Nanoscience, Physics and Chemistry of Advanced Materials from Trinity College Dublin. Conor grew up in Dublin and his sporting interests include football, hurling and rugby. He was a member of Dublin University Boat Club (DUBC) at Trinity college Dublin during his undergraduate degree.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Connor Sherwin</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/connor-sherwin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/connor-sherwin/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Connor completed his PhD at the University of Southampton Department of Chemistry in 2024 with Prof. Andrea Russell. His PhD focussed on designing a spectro-electrochemical cell for operando XAS measurements of gas evolving and gas consuming reactions. This work focussed on characterising state of the art catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction, carbon dioxide reduction reaction and oxygen reduction reaction.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jack Swallow</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/jack-swallow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/jack-swallow/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Jack did his undergraduate and PhD at the University of Liverpool, studying in the department of physics. Here he focussed on understanding factors affecting the performance of wide band gap metal-oxide semiconductors and transparent conducting oxides. He is now employed as a PDRA in the group of Robert Weatherup, at the Materials department at Oxford.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Thermocatalysis</title><link>http://localhost:1313/research/thermocatalysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/research/thermocatalysis/</guid><description>Redesigning chemical industry processes to use sustainable feedstocks instead of fossil fuels.</description></item><item><title>Electronic Structure Simulations</title><link>http://localhost:1313/research/electronic-structure/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/research/electronic-structure/</guid><description>Computational research using DFT and CTM theory to predict properties and interpret experimental findings.</description></item><item><title>Trevor Binford</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/trevor-binford/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/trevor-binford/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After growing up in the US (in Los Angeles, California and Austin, Texas), Trevor moved to the UK for university. He completed a BA at Trinity Hall, Cambridge in 2019, studying Natural Sciences with a focus on chemistry. He then undertook an MPhil at Pembroke College, Cambridge, researching supercapacitors for CO&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;2&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; capture under the supervision of Alex Forse and finishing in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Boruch Epstein</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/boruch-epstein/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/boruch-epstein/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Boruch completed his MChem in the University of Manchester, studying Chemistry. His previous research experience is in the Popelier group and Walton group, both in Manchester.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boruch dabbles in programming and anything computer related. He is also a committed bibliophile and can be easily waylaid by a strategically placed book. Boruch is aware of both outdoors and sport, and one day intends to experience both.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jasper Singh</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/jasper-singh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/jasper-singh/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Jasper joined the Weatherup group in October 2021 to investigate the electrode-electrolyte interface in Li-Ion batteries. He is currently a first year DPhil student in the Department of Materials at St Edmund Hall, University of Oxford. Jasper received First Class honours in his bachelors degree in Chemistry from the University of Warwick prior to this (2018-2021). He grew up in London and his sporting interests include rugby, football, and swimming. Jasper was part of the University of Warwick Rugby Football Club senior executive team (2019-2021) and is now a member of the St Edmund Hall Rugby Football Club.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Soumyajit Maitra</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/soumyajit-maitra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/soumyajit-maitra/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Soumyajit completed his undergrad in Chemical Engineering at the University of Calcutta in India. During his undergrad, he worked on photoelectrochemical water splitting, Dye-Sensitised solar cells, perovskite solar cells and electrocatalytic water splitting at different research institutes, namely, Bose Institute, JU, IIEST and IIT Bombay. After finishing his undergrad in 2020, he took up the role of a research assistant at the Indian Association for the Cultivation of Science (IACS) and CSIR-CSIO with an Institute Fellowship, where he worked on 2D materials for photoelectrochemical water splitting and supercapacitors. He also worked on DFT calculations of 2D materials for photocatalysis as a collaboration project with Wuhan University of Technology, China and U-Namur, Belgium. From HT 2023, Soumyajit is pursuing a DPhil with a Clarendon and Trinity Whitehead Scholarship, supervised by Prof. Sebastian Bonilla and Prof. Robert Weatherup.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Catherine Kohler</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/catherine-kohler/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/catherine-kohler/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2023, Catie graduated from the University of Sheffield with an MEng in Materials Science and Engineering. Her final year research project focused on the influence of counterions on biotemplating layered transition metal oxide nanowires for potential cathode application. Catie previously took part in the Faraday Undergraduate Student Experience (FUSE) with FutureCat to create educational resources for students. Her integrated masters offered an accredited industrial placement, where she worked at Exawatt Ltd as a Research Analyst. During her time in Sheffield, she picked up a keen interest in climbing and spent many weekends exploring the Peak district.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sirui Li</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/sirui-li/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/sirui-li/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Sirui joined the group in 2023, as a DPhil student. She completed her BSc Materials Science and Engineering from a 2+2 joint program from Central South University and University of Manchester. After completing bachelor’s degree, in 2022, Sirui took MRes in Nanomaterials from Imperial College London, working on the topic of photoelectrochemical water splitting with transient absorption spectroscopy. In her spare time, she enjoys movies, hiking, baking, and crocheting.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Helen Engelhardt</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/helen-engelhardt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/helen-engelhardt/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Helen joined the group as a DPhil student in October 2024, supported by the Clarendon Fund and an Oxford-Wolfson-Marriott scholarship. She graduated from the University of Waterloo in 2024 with a BASc of Nanotechnology Engineering with Honours. Her final project was a treatment system for removing microplastics from water using iron oxide nanoparticles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During undergrad, Helen researched CO2 reduction electrochemistry, synthesis of various shapes of gold nanoparticles, and the electrochemical stability of gold nanoparticle catalysts with the Klinkova lab. She also spent 4 months studying metal foil battery electrodes at NRC-Nano with the Fleischauer group. Helen has also interned in industry: she spent 8 months working on separation of Co and Ni for battery recycling at SiTration, and 8 months in microfluidics design for nanomedicine at Precision Nanosystems.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Yifan Bai</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/yifan-bai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/yifan-bai/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Yifan joined the Weatherup Group in 2025 to investigate the electrode–electrolyte interface in lithium-ion batteries. He graduated from Imperial College London in 2025 with an MEng in Materials Science and Engineering, awarded with First Class Honours. During his final-year project, he worked in Professor Stephen Skinner’s group, focusing on enhancing the performance of solid oxide fuel cell cathodes at intermediate temperatures. Beyond research, Yifan enjoys swimming, reading, and jogging.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sevinç Yağmur Bekler</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/sevinc-yagmur-bekler/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/sevinc-yagmur-bekler/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Yağmur joined the group as an MSc by Research student in 2024. Prior to this, she graduated from Sabancı University in 2023 with a BSc degree in Materials Science and Nano Engineering, with minors in Chemistry and Physics. She worked in Prof. Gözde Ince’s group, and her graduation project on a molecularly imprinted nanotube-based chemosensor for cancer diagnosis resulted in a joint publication. Additionally, she completed an exchange semester at the National University of Singapore in 2022. Beyond academia, Yağmur enjoys taking walks in nature, playing tennis, cooking, travelling, and singing in the college choir.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>