<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Alumni on Weatherup Group</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/</link><description>Recent content in Alumni on Weatherup Group</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aryan Dixit</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/aryan-dixit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/aryan-dixit/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Aryan is a 4th year materials science student at Mansfield College, completing his Part II master’s project in the Weatherup group. After graduating, Aryan is keen on a career in consulting in a science and technology-related industry. In his spare time, he enjoys playing football, squash and board games and loves spending time with his mates.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chanisa Phuralrakul</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/chanisa-phuralrakul/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/chanisa-phuralrakul/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Chanisa is a 4th year undergraduate in the Department of Materials at the Queen’s College, University of Oxford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to starting her undergraduate degree, she went to secondary school in Cheltenham and the Netherlands. In her spare time, she enjoys reading and going on runs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Elizabeth Jones</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/elizabeth-jones/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/elizabeth-jones/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2020 Lizzie graduated from the University of St Andrews with an MSci in Chemistry and Physics. Lizzie loved being in the coastal town for 5 years, but never took up golf and spent more time in pubs instead! During her undergraduate degree Lizzie started playing korfball (a mixed gender sport which is a combination of basketball and netball) and hopes to continue to play in Oxford. Lizzie grew up in a rural village on Dartmoor and enjoys going for walks with her family when going back to visit. During the summers of 2017, 2018, and 2019 Lizzie worked as a research intern at KP Technology (Wick), University of St Andrews, and Diamond Light Source, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fabian Bourdeaux</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/fabian-bourdeaux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/fabian-bourdeaux/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Fabian is a 4th Year Materials science student at St Anne’s college. Under a scheme from the Henry Royce institute, he interned in the Weatherup group in the summer of 2022 helping set up the nanoparticle deposition system being used now. In his free time he enjoys going running, playing guitar, and acting.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Greta Thompson</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/greta-thompson/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/greta-thompson/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Greta is a final year materials science student studying at The Queens College. She is completing her master&amp;rsquo;s year research project in Robert Weatherup’s group. In the summer of 2019 she completed a FUSE internship sponsored by the Faraday Institution, where she worked in Mauro Pasta’s group in Oxford researching the solid-state battery material LLZTO. Presenting her research poster at the Faraday conference led to a virtual internship in the summer of 2020 with the early-stage start-up Breathe Battery Technologies. In her spare time she enjoys playing football for Headington Ladies and getting involved in the entrepreneurial scene in Oxford.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Inigo Stratton</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/inigo-stratton/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/inigo-stratton/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Inigo is a 4th Year Materials science student at St Catherine&amp;rsquo;s College. In his free time, he enjoys doing cue sports, karate and exploring entrepreneurial ventures.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jessica Wen</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/jessica-wen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/jessica-wen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Jessica joined the Energy Materials Interfaces group in October 2020 for her Integrated Master’s project as part of her undergraduate studies in Materials Science at Oxford. In her spare time, Jess enjoys playing violin, table tennis, badminton and football.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jodie Charlton</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/jodie-charlton/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/jodie-charlton/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After completing her MChem at the University of Manchester in 2018, Jodie decided to venture out to the land of The Southrons to join the Weatherup group and inadvertently live out her life as a beamtime junkie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a proud Northumbrian and 80-year-old granny at heart, Jodie&amp;rsquo;s outside interests involve reading, crafting, boozy baking, complaining about the noisy neighbours and arguing about where the north (of England) truly begins.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Joshua Gibson</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/joshua-gibson/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/joshua-gibson/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Josh joined our group in November 2019 to perform ultra-high vacuum (UHV) studies on battery surfaces during their operation as part of the Faraday characterisation project. He attained his PhD from the University of Nottingham by looking at the interaction of small molecules with ionic liquids utilising UHV techniques. This involved both laboratory based experiments as well as use of external facilities (Diamond Light Source). Following this he held a teaching position within the School of Chemistry at Nottingham, before moving to the University of Birmingham to investigate the effect of electrical potentials on the formation of biologically relevant surfaces. Josh spent his childhood and teenage years growing up and working on farms, so consequently enjoys visiting the nearby Cotswolds and Chilterns to go walking in the countryside. On rainy days he enjoys playing guitar or learning new skills with any spare time.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Leanne Jones</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/leanne-jones/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/leanne-jones/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Leanne obtained her PhD at the University of Liverpool studying the electronic structure of transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) using X-ray photoemission spectroscopy coupled with theoretical calculations. As well as TMDs, she has been involved in collaborative projects looking at batteries, PV absorbers, wide band gap oxides and transparent conducting oxides with multiple groups across the University. Her primary focus is x-ray photoemission spectroscopy (XPS) of these materials including both soft and hard XPS. In her free time Leanne enjoys going on long walks (that usually end up at the pub!) in the countryside, watching any tv show that includes drag queens, and reading history books.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lijin An</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/lijin-an/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/lijin-an/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Lijin joined the group and started as a DPhil student in 2021. She graduated from Imperial College London in 2020 with an MRes degree in Nanomaterials where she worked on a project exploring the electronic properties of defective graphene-based 2D heterostructures. Her major was Materials Science and Engineering and her undergraduate lab experience at Wuhan University of Technology focused on photocatalysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lijin is always excited about trying new things. Among all the intriguing activities, she is most passionate about cinema and enjoys stage play, reading and hiking.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Michael Fraser</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/michael-fraser/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/michael-fraser/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Michael joined Professor Robert Weatherup’s group in October 2019 as a DPhil student. Prior to coming to Oxford, Michael received his undergraduate degree in Pure and Applied Chemistry (BSc) in 2018 from the University of Strathclyde. He then worked 14 months as a graduate for AGM Batteries Ltd. in Scotland developing prototype high performance lithium-ion batteries for automotive applications. In his spare time Michael enjoys Skiing, watching and playing football.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Namrata Ramesh</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/namrata-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/namrata-ramesh/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I received my BA with Honors in Physics from UC Berkeley in 2020, where I worked with the Ginsberg Group as an undergraduate researcher. My undergraduate thesis investigated the self-assembly of gold nanocrystal superlattices by analyzing x-ray photon correlation spectroscopy (XPCS) data. I joined Oxford Materials as a Masters by Research candidate under Dr. Rebecca Nicholls and Prof. Robert Weatherup in Michaelmas 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Owen Lawton</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/owen-lawton/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/owen-lawton/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Owen is a 4th Year Materials Science student at St Catherine&amp;rsquo;s College. In his free time, he enjoys swimming and photography.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pravin Didwal</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/pravin-didwal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/pravin-didwal/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Pravin Didwal joined as a postdoctoral research fellow at the Department of Materials, University of Oxford in October 2021 to work on the Faraday degradation project as part of Robert Weatherup’s Group. He undertook his PhD from Chonnam National University, South Korea as a Brain Korea fellow-2016. He completed his MPhil and MSc in Physics from University of Pune, India. During his PhD work was based on designing highly efficient composite solid electrolytes for high-performance all-state-state Li-ion batteries. He has worked on the development of different types of composite solid polymer electrolytes and analysis of their interface and interphases with cathode/anode by several characterization techniques such as by FIB-TEM, XPS, AFM, and ToF-SIMS.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Renkai Zhang</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/renkai-zhang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/renkai-zhang/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Renkai is a 4th year Materials Science student in St Catherine&amp;rsquo;s College at the University of Oxford, working under the supervision of Rob Weatherup. His current research investigates the development of suspended graphene membranes for analytical characterisation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Roxanna Roskilly</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/roxanna-roskilly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/roxanna-roskilly/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Rosanna is a 4th year materials science student at Mansfield College, completing her Part II master’s project in the Weatherup group. In summer 2021, she interned with the Henry Royce Institute roadmapping materials challenges for the hydrogen economy. In her free time she likes walking, fitness, badminton, and drawing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Thomas Bricknell</title><link>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/thomas-bricknell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/people/alumni/thomas-bricknell/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Tom is a Part II Undergraduate Student in Materials Science at the University of Oxford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He joined the University in 2018 after having completed A levels at Hereford Cathedral School. His hobbies include playing Rugby, Football and Cricket and singing for his College, St Edmund Hall.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>